SMITH KAMLESH GAJJAR

Mumbai, Maharashtra

smith.gajjar@gmail.com www.smithgajjar.dev smith-gajjar smithg09

Senior Full Stack Developer and Solutions Architect with 2.5 years of experience in building applications and open source projects using several languages and JavaScript frameworks, managing and optimizing backend infrastructure including deployment, scalability, performance and 3rd party service integrations.

EXPERIENCE

Tekie [₹ Senior Full Stack Developer

June 2022 – Present

Remote

Full Stack Developer

June 2021 - June 2022

Frontend Developer Intern

Feb 2021 - June 2021

- Built user facing modules for MVP product, a Progressive Web App based on **Reactis** and **Redux** and a Desktop Application using **Electron.is**
- Developed, Managed and Optimized API's and backend architecture for enhanced scalability and performance utilizing Nodejs, GraphQL and Redis Caching.
- Developed and Managed Internal Reporting and tooling architecture for Business Team utilizing Node, ETL Map Reduce Process (From MongoDB to SQL), PostgreSQL and Python (Flask)
- Integration of different 3rd party services such as GSuit, Newrelic, Sentry, Elastic Search, Stellate (GraphQL Caching) and **GA/GTM** to improve and monitor application performance.
- · Managed and Optimized deployment infrastructure and Configured CI/CD on Github/Jenkins based of Kubernetes, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Azure Services and AWS Services such as EC2, EKS, ECR, S3, Elastic Transcoder and CloudFront.
- Developed and Contributed to open-source NPM libraries for platform, mongodb-aggregation-builder, <u>tekie-content-editor</u>, <u>tekie-blockly</u>. Developed and Led many <u>Proof of Concept's for Product Development</u>.
- Interacting and engaging in discussions with stakeholders from various departments to determine and deliver optimal tech solutions aligned with business requirements.
- Mentored, Guided and led a team of 7 in spearheading the product development and seamless migration of an product suite. Encouraged code hygiene and best practices while building along with peer code reviews.

InVideo 📝 Mumbai

Front-end Developer Intern

June 2019 - July 2019

- Built new user facing modules for MVP product based on **Angular** 7
- Converting designs from and Solutions Architect into pixel-perfect responsive screens.
- Helped in fixing cross-browser inconsistencies in the interface using **BrowserStack**.

PROJECTS

mongodb-aggregation-builder 🗹

• MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline Builder NPM Library built using Typescript.

GraphQL Nodejs Backend Starter

• A Typesafe NodeJS Backend Server Boilerplate/Starter Built using Typescript/MongoDB/GraphQL/Redis.

Blockly NPM Library ✓

• Customised Blockly React Wrapper around Google's official Blockly Library.

Flashify 7

• Flashcard Mobile App Built using React Native.

View all projects n smithg09

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: JavaScript, Python, SQL, NoSQL NodeJS, GraphQL, ReactJS, Angular, TypeScript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, NGINX, Electron, HTML, CSS/Sass, React Native., Next.js, Redux.

Tools: AWS, Azure, Sentry, Jenkins, Git, Webpack, Notion, Vercel, Docker, Jest, Asana, Jira, Trello

EDUCATION

Vivekanand Educational Society's Institute of Technology

2018 - 2021

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer Science

Mumbai, Maharashtra

K.J.Somaiya Polytechnic

2015 - 2018

Diploma In Computer Engineering

Mumbai, Maharashtra